<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Kieran Tully]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Kieran Tully]]></description>
        <link>http://ktully.net/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 15:09:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://ktully.net/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 15:09:10 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3 days to OCA Java SE 8 Programmer I (1Z0-808)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>3 days to OCA Java SE 8 Programmer I (1Z0-808)</h1>,<h2>Introduction</h2>,<p>Here are some tips on the strategies I used and some things I wish I’d known in advance.</p>,<p>DRAFT - Work in progress. More to come :)</p>,<h3>Disclaimer</h3>,<p>It’s not advisable to cram for any exam. You will get far more out of the training if you invest weeks or months preparing properly. I was in a non-ideal situation where I couldn’t postpone the exam but had not done any preparation. The day before the exam, I fully expected to fail.</p>,<p>There is no guarantee that using these tips will allow you to pass. Bear in mind also that I have been programming in Java on and off for two decades.</p>,<h2>Preparation</h2>,<h3>General</h3>,<ul><li><strong>Know where your exam centre is</strong> and how you will get there on the day. Ideally go there beforehand to sus out public transport, parking etc.</li><li><strong>Have a plan for your exam</strong> based on the duration and number of questions. For example, if you have 150 mins to do the exam and 70 questions to answer, you might plan to allow 2 minutes per question with 10 minutes for review at the end.</li></ul>,<h2>Exam day</h2>,<ul><li><strong>Bring foam or wax ear plugs</strong>, so that the noise of other candidates doesn’t disturb you. My exam centre provided ear plugs and I was very glad they did. I wouldn’t have thought to bring them myself.</li></ul>,<h3>Getting there</h3>,<ul><li><strong>Review your summary notes and mnemonics on your phone on the way. </strong>If you’re driving, have your phone read them aloud to you<strong>. </strong>Otherwise skim read them yourself.</li><li><strong>Aim to arrive at least 15 minutes early</strong>, or 30 minutes if you have not attended a proctored Oracle exam before. This will allow you plenty of time to complete the necessary registration preliminaries (remember there might be a queue!) and use the bathroom.</li></ul>,<h3>Before the exam</h3>,<ul><li><strong>Ask for extra writing materials</strong> before entering the exam room. My exam centre provided dry erase sheets. I ran out of space and wasted time erasing previous work with a tissue. I could have asked for more sheets (from the very helpful attendant at the front desk), but wasn’t certain of the procedure and didn’t want to waste time.</li></ul>,<h3>During the exam</h3>,<p><strong>Pretend you are the Java compiler.</strong></p>,<ul><li><strong>If one of the answers is “does not compile” or “compilation error</strong> on line <em>N” </em>you know there may be a compilation error in the presented source code.</li></ul>,<p><strong>Pretend you are the Java Virtual Machine.</strong></p>,<p><strong>Time keeping.</strong></p>,<ul><li><strong>Check in regularly</strong><strong>against your plan</strong> during the exam. For example, at 30 minutes in, you should have about 15 questions completed. You may need to speed up if you are behind.</li><li><strong>Don’t panic if you are behind.</strong> Some questions are harder than others and will take more time. I got a bunch of easier questions in the middle which allowed me to make up time. If you must move on, strike out (on PC, right click) the answers you’re sure are not correct. This will speed up your review process later.</li><li><strong>Provide an answer to every question. </strong>Press the <em>Review </em>button at the end to check. Pick the most plausible of the answers you did not eliminate in your earlier pass. You will never lose marks by guessing, but you may gain marks!</li></ul>,<h3>After the exam</h3>,<ul><li><strong>Celebrate! Pass or fail, you have definitely learnt something </strong>about the material.</li><li><strong>You should get an email with a link to your results within 30 minutes.</strong></li><li>The results screen will list <strong>which exam objectives you lost marks on. Review the material on these</strong> to solidify your learning.</li><li>If you passed, congratulations! Take some time to relax, then prepare for your next exam. </li><li>If you failed, hang your head up high. You were brave enough to take the exam and expose yourself to the possibility of failure. If you can’t fail, you can’t learn. Many competent programmers are not good test takers. And many good test takers are not competent programmers!</li></ul>,<h2>Resources</h2>,<ul><li>My exam centre was quiet and staffed by a friendly and efficient woman whose name I’ve forgotten. Use them if you’re in Dublin. TODO link</li><li>Exam discount package with retake voucher  TODO link</li><li>Other tips: https://transcender.wordpress.com/2011/01/27/oracle-exam-strategies/</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://education.oracle.com/pls/web_prod-plq-dad/db_pages.getpage?page_id=5001&amp;get_params=p_exam_id:1Z0-808</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">884aa4a4-b8d9-48a9-9e67-53074c41a9c2</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 13:05:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>